Guide to the Jack O'Brien Papers AIA.067
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jack O'Brien Papers
1861-2021
1970-2018
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
O'Brien, Jack
AIA.067
31.12 Linear Feet in 56 legal sized manuscript boxes, 2 oversize flat boxes, 1 card box, 1 media box, 3 letter sized half-manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box for rolled storage, 4 folders in a shared flat box, and 6 folders in a shared flat oversized box
4.7 Gigabytes in 36 computer files
Jack O'Brien (May 16, 1938) is an engaged member of the Ancient Order of Hibernians (AOH) District of Columbia State Board. He has been active in various efforts to install memorials to significant Irish and Irish American people and serves as National Co-Chairman of the John Barry Memorial Project. In 2015, he was selected to be the Grand Marshal of the St. Patrick's Day Parade in Washington, D.C. This collection consists of materials created and collected by O'Brien regarding his involvement with the Washington, D.C. AOH, as well as his interest in republicanism related to Northern Ireland, Brexit's impact on Ireland, and Irish history and culture.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jack O'Brien. The accession number associated with this gift is 2012.039. O'Brien has donated multiple accretions between 2012 and 2022.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into series by topic:
Series I: The Troubles in Northern Ireland
Sub-series I.A: 1981 Hunger Strikes
Sub-series I.B: Irish American Organizations
Sub-series I.C: Extradition Treaty
Sub-series I.D: Press Clippings
Series II: Northern Ireland Post Troubles
Series III: Belfast Project (Boston College and the IRA Oral History Tapes)
Series IV: Monuments and Commemorations
Series V: Ancient Order of Hibernians (AOH)
Series VI: Irish History
Series VII: Jack O'Brien - Personal Materials
Within each series, the materials have been arranged alphabetically and grouped thematically, when possible.
Biographical Note
Jack O'Brien (May 16, 1938) is an engaged member of the Ancient Order of Hibernians (AOH) District of Columbia State Board. He has been active in various efforts to install memorials to significant Irish and Irish American people and serves as National Co-Chairman of the John Barry Memorial Project. In 2015, he was selected to be the Grand Marshal of the St. Patrick's Day Parade in Washington, D.C. Between the 1970s and 1990s, O'Brien was a member of various Irish American organizations, such as the Irish Northern Aid Committee, and helped to raise money to support the on-going Republican movement in Northern Ireland. He continues to champion Irish history and Irish culture through his participation in Irish heritage festivals, St. Patrick's Day parades, as well as with his patronage of institutions like the Irish Railroad Workers Museum and the Irish American Cultural Institute.
Scope and Contents
The Jack O'Brien Papers consists of materials created and collected by O'Brien regarding his engagement with the Washington, D.C. Ancient Order of Hibernians (AOH), his interest in republicanism related to Northern Ireland, Brexit's impact on Ireland, Irish history and culture, as well as his involvement to create and install physical memorials to significant figures in Irish and Irish American history.
The first three series of this collection relates to various aspects of the "The Troubles" in Northern Ireland. The Troubles refers to the 30 year conflict between Nationalists (Irish or Roman Catholics) and Unionists (British or Protestants). Series I: The Troubles in Northern Ireland focuses upon the actual conflict itself between the mid-1960s to 1998, Series II: Northern Ireland Post Troubles focuses upon the legacy of the Troubles after the signing of the Good Friday Agreement, and Series III: Belfast Project (Boston College and the IRA Tapes) examines the legal battles between Boston College and the British authorities attempting to obtain copies of IRA oral histories recorded as part of Boston College's "Belfast Project." It should be noted, due to the large volume of materials within the Jack O'Brien Papers that specifically addressed the 1981 Hunger Strike, Irish American Organzations active during the Troubles, controversial U.S.-U.K. Extradition Treaties, and news coverage of this period, specific sub-series related to each of these topics was created.
The latter half of the Jack O'Brien Papers focuses upon O'Brien's personal interests and affiliations. Series IV and VI are related as they both focus upon Irish history. O'Brien was integral to the creation of many monuments commemorating great Irish individuals, such as Commodore John Barry, Irish military units, such as the Irish Brigade, as well as important events in Irish history, such as the Great Famine. These activities are documented in Series IV: Monuments and Commemorations. Series VI: Irish History provides historical context for subjects like the Irish Brigade, the Great Famine, the Fenian Movement, the Easter Rising, and Irish involvment in the Revolutionary War.
Jack O'Brien continues to be an active member of the AOH and his participation is reflected in the materials found within Series V. This series contains information pertaining to the history of the AOH, divisional newsletters recounting the activities of various branches of the AOH, fundraising efforts, AOH convention materials, as well as numerous copies of the AOH newspaper, The National Hibernian Digest.
Finally, Series VII: Jack O'Brien - Personal Materials, documents O'Brien's patronage of various Irish American institutions like the Irish American Cultural Institute and Irish Railroad Workers Museum, his family history, his love of Ireland and his Irish heritage, as well as his continued enagement with his local Irish American community through events like the St. Patrick's Day Parade and Irish Festivals.
Materials in this collection include correspondence, flyers, newsletters, photographs, newspapers, speeches, official reports, press releases, interviews, book excerpts, posters, newspaper clippings, stickers, brochures, vinyl records, VHS tapes, CDs, an audio reel, St. Patrick's Day magazines, business cards, buttons, email printouts, legal documents, government documents, architectural drawings, and commemorative materials.
Related Materials
For more information about Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive's collection of Irish American newspapers and periodicals, see the Guide to the Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals Collection AIA.004.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns. Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
Appraisal
In 2021, 3 record cartons were deaccessioned from the collection. The boxes contained commercially published books, several articles of clothing, and duplicate personal photographs.
Separated Materials
In 2021, 3 record cartons containing Irish American newspapers and periodicals were removed from the Jack O'Brien Papers and placed in to the "Guide to the Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals" collection (AIA.004).
Irish Americans -- Societies, etc.; Northern Ireland -- History -- 1998; Irish Americans -- History.; Irish Americans -- Newspapers.; Irish Americans -- Ethnic identity.; Northern Ireland -- History -- 1968-1998; Ulster (Northern Ireland and Ireland); Bloody Sunday, Derry, Northern Ireland, 1972.; Belfast (Northern Ireland); Antietam -- Battle of, Md -- 1862; Ireland -- History -- Famine, 1845-1852; European Union -- Great Britain; Political posters.; Correspondence.; Newsletters.; Photographs.; Calendars.; Audiocassettes.; VHS; CD-ROMs.; Ireland -- History -- Easter Rising, 1916; Irish Hunger Strike, Northern Ireland, 1981.; Great Britain -- Treaties, etc. -- Ireland -- 1998 April 10; Great Britain -- Treaties, etc. -- United States -- 1972 June 8; Saint Patrick's Day.; Gettysburg (Pa.); Thatcher, Margaret; Biaggi, Mario; Reagan, Ronald; Irish Northern Aid Committee; Paisley, Ian, 1926-2014; United States. Army of the Potomac. Irish Brigade; Irish American Unity Conference; Adams, Gerry, 1948-; Moloney, Ed, 1948-; Finucane, Patrick; Mountbatten, Louis, Earl, Mountbatten of Burma, 1900-1979; Long Kesh (Prison); Sands, Bobby, 1954-1981; Armagh Prison (Armagh, Northern Ireland); Clan-na-Gael; Barry, John, Commodore, 1745-1803; Meagher, Thomas Francis, 1823-1867; Ancient Order of Hibernians; Boston College; Emmet, Robert, 1778-1803; Sinn Fein
- Series I: The Troubles in Northern Ireland, 1964-2017 (inclusive), 1971-1989 (bulk); 11.58 Linear Feet in 22 legal manuscripts box, 3 folders in an additional legal manuscripts box, 13 folders in an oversized box, 5 folders in an additional oversized box, rolled storage, and 3 folders in a shared oversized box; 3.17 Gigabytes on 1 DVD-R disc
  Scope and Contents
  This series focuses upon the Northern Ireland conflict, commonly referred to as "The Troubles," which was a 30 year conflict fought between Nationalists (mainly self-identified Irish or Roman Catholics) and Unionists (mainly self-identified British or Protestants). It contains information relating to numerous subjects including, but not limited to: Armagh prison, Long Kesh prison, British reports on Northern Irish terrorist activities, anti-Margaret Thatcher and anti-British propaganda, news coverage of the Provisional Irish Republican Army's (IRA) assasination of Lord Louis Mountbatten, Bloody Sunday, the trial of John DeLorean, MacBride Principles, plastic and rubber bullets, as well as human rights in Northern Ireland.
  The Jack O'Brien Papers contains a large volume of material related to the Troubles, but within this series, it became evident that four categories featured more heavily than others. To reflect this, specific sub-series focusing upon the 1981 Hunger Strike, Irish American Organizations, the U.S.-U.K. Extradition Treaties, and news coverage of the Troubles have also been created.
  Materials in this series include correspondence, flyers, newsletters, photographs, speeches, official reports, Congresssional Records, press releases, interviews, book excerpts, posters, audio cassettes, and newspaper clippings.
  Arrangement
  The materials in both the larger series and sub-series have been arranged alphabetically.
  - "Accumulation and the Irish Crisis" (Denis O'Hearn), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address by John Hume MP at Catholic University Convocation, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Address delivered by the Minister-Designate for Foreign Affairs Senator James Dooge, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Affidavit - Birdie Letter, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AFL-CIO Legislative Proposal Regarding Unemployment in Northern Ireland, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Against Violence in Ireland (Desmond Wilson), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Americans for Human Rights and Self-Determination in Ireland, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Amnesty International, 1978, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ancient Order of the Hibernians Memos, 1983-1988, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anglo-Irish Joint Studies, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Armagh Prison, 1973, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Bagpipes & Bullets", undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Banner, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Belfast Children's Summer Program, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bernadette Devlin McAliskey, 1983, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A Bill to Amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - A Bill to Amend the Immigration and Nationality Act, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Blank Cards and Postcards, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Book Excerpt - Ireland Free State or Nation? (Diarmaid O Suilleabhain), undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Boycott British Goods, 1972, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19, Box 57, Folder 4)
  - British Information Services Reports, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "British Occupation of Northeast Ireland", undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bumper Stickers, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Calendar, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Captive Voice: The Voice of the Irish Republican Prisoners of War, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - CBS News Transcript: Interview with Rev. Ian Paisley, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Center for Irish Studies - Catholic University, 1980, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Children's Friendship Project for Northern Ireland, Inc., 1996 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Children in the Crossfire TV Show, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Christmas Cards (Political), 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "A Chronicle of Oppression in Northern Ireland", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Catholic League Newsletter, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Clare Short, MP, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Human Rights Caucus, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Records, 1975-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Congressman Mario Biaggi Newsletters, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6-8, Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence - Foreign Governments, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - George P. Weeks, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - U.S. Government, 1971-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7-8, Box 4, Folder 1)
  - County Reports on Human Rights Practices in 1981, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Crunch Has Come (Frankie O'Brien), 1981; cuid42464 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Death of Lord Louis Mountbatten, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - A Decade of Deceit, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Directory of Organizations, Establishments, and Individuals Promoting Irish Culture in the Washington Metropolitan Area, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Eamon de Valera, Address to Joint House of Congress, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "The Effects of Emergency Legislation", undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Emergency Conference on Political Extradition, Detention, and Deportation, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "End Internment" Poster, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - "England Out of Ireland" Poster, undated (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Essays and Speeches, 1978-1986 (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
  - Flyers and Brochures, 1983-1996 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Federal Communications Commission, 1971-1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Policy Issue: Northern Ireland, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Formation of National Committee on Visa Denial, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Frank McManus, MP, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Georgia Fleming, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Gerry Adams Visit Washington, DC, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "The H-Blocks: The New Internment", undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hamilton Fish, Jr. Newsletter, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Historical Patterns in Ireland's Foreign Policy, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "How the Orangemen Began", undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - If An Agent Knocks: Federal Investigators and Your Rights, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Industrial Investment in Northern Ireland, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Informer (A Sinn Fein Publication), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Interchurch Emergency Fund to Ireland, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - International Tribunal on Britain's Presence in Ireland, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Institute for Economic Justice, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ireland: An Occupied Country, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Ireland for the Irish (Kissie Woolie), undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - The Irish American Voice, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Irish Freedom Petition, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Irish Plank in the Democratic Platform", 1984 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Irish Political Prisoners Childrens' Funds, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Irish POWs Imprisoned By British, 1976-1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Irish Republican Movement Today", undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - John DeLorean, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Joint Action Committee for Irish Political Prisoners, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Joseph Doherty, 1987-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - "Keeping Catholics in their Place", 1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Kevin Douleary, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Kevin Lynch - Murdered" Poster, undated (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Liz Curtis, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Lost Liberties: The Offences Against the State Act, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - MacBride Principles, 1988, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - McCarren-Walter Act, 1987, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - The McGrath Report, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Members of the Heavy Gang, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Michael McCartan: An Innocent Catholic Boy Shot Dead by the RUC, 23 July 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Michael O'Rourke, 1980-1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Ministry of Defence Reports on Northern Ireland, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Moore Family - Fire Tragedy, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Nicky Kelly, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Northern Ireland - Ministry of Reconcilliation, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Northern Ireland: A Religious Conflict?", undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Nuachtan, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "An Open Letter to Irish Catholics" (Des Wilson), 1988 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - The Orange Order: A Root Cause of Hatred, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Patricia Ann Willis, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Patriot Game - 1972, 2015; cuid42463 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_2)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
  - Plastic Bullets, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "Plastic and Rubber Bullets" Poster, undated (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - "Pope John Paul II and Human Rights", 1979 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, 1979-1997 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - The Price of Justice, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 084, Audiocassette 067.0004)
  - Prison Struggle, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Proclamation - Human Rights Day for Northern Ireland, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Provisional IRA Posters, undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Race Relations Legislation, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Re: Congressional Enquiries, British Government Reply to the Department of State, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Real Terror Network (Patricia Ann Willis), 1983 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Remember the Prisoners and their Dependents in Jail for a United Ireland, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Report of Committee of Inquiry into Police Interrogation Procedures in Northern Ireland, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Report on Human Rights Practices in Countries Receiving U.S. Aid, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Reports of Unusual Incident on May 22, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Resolutions Commending Martin Galvin for Indomitable Courage in the Face of Inveterate Oppression, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Resolutions on Ireland, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbooks, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 1, Box 10)
  - Seamus Burns, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Senate Judiciary Subcommittee on Security and Terrorism, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Silent Too Long, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sinn Fein Posters, undated (Flat-file-folder 7)
  - "The Soldier's Song" (Irish National Anthem) Sheet Music, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - The Special Powers Act, Northern Ireland, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - St. Patrick's Day Parade, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - State Terrorism, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Statement from British Embassy Re: 1981 Human Rights Report on the UK, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Statement of the Honorable Thomas S. Foley - Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Statement of Paul S. Quinn on Behalf of the Committee for a New Ireland before the Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East House Committee on Foreign Affairs, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Subcommittee on Security and Terrorism Hearing - Senator Jeremiah Denton, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Statutes in Force: Fugitive Offenders Act 1967, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Summit Talk Between Ireland and Britain, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - "Support the Five Demands" Poster, undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - "Support the IRA" Posters, undated (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - "Take an Active Part in Ireland's Future", 1983 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Take the Faroes for Example (Desmond Fennell), undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Testimony of Gerald E. Coleman - Subcommittee on Europe and the MIddle East, Foreign Affiairs Committee, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Testimony of the Honorable Brian Donnelly Before the Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East International Fund for Ireland, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Testimony Before the House Subcommittee for Europe and the Middle East on the International Fund for Ireland by Father Sean McManus, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - "They May Kill the Revolutionary, But Never the Revolution" Poster, undated (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Towards Lasting Peace in Ireland (Sinn Fein), 1992 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - "Trip to Washington", 1983 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Ulster Commentary, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Understanding the Irish Conflict, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 084, Audiocassette 067.0003)
  - United States, Britain, Ireland: A Special Special Relationship (Leonard Brenner), undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Various posters related to "The Troubles", undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Violation of Human Rights in Northern Ireland, 1968-1978 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - "Violations of Human Rights in Northern Ireland Listed According to the Articles of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights", undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - "Wanted For Murder" Margaret Thatcher Posters, undated (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - "Were These Men Criminals? Britain Said Yes!" Poster, undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Why the United States Government and the People of the United States Should be Concerned with the Problem of Northern Ireland", undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - The Writing Campaign, 1993, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Sub-series I.A: 1981 Hunger Strike, 1980-2020; 0.85 Linear Feet in one legal sized manuscript box, 2 folder in an oversized box, rolled storage, and 1 folder in an additional oversized box.
    This series focuses upon the 1981 Hunger Strike, specifically the public outcry against the actions of the British government and public support for the striking prisoners. Some of the material in this series focuses on Bobby Sands' election to Parliament while imprisoned at HMS Maze Prison (also known as Long Kesh Prison) and his death. There are also commemorative materials remembering the legacy of the 1981 Hunger Strike.
    This series contains newspaper clippings, political newsletters, correspondence, posters, book excerpts, information brochures, flyers, press releases, commemoration materials, and documents from Irish American organizations like the Irish Northern Aid Committee and the Irish National Caucus.
    The materials in this series have been arranged alphabetically.
    - 1981 Hunger Strike: America Reacts (NYU Virtual Exhibit), undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 1981 Hunger Strike Commemorations, 1986, 2001, 2011, 2017 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The 1981 Hunger Strike: It's Roots and Significance in Irish History (Tomas W. McLoughlin), 2011 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - An Analysis of the Washington Post's Coverage of the Hunger Strike in Northern Ireland, September 1980-August 1981 (Grace Lynch) (Box 11, Folder 4)